漫威《神盾局特工》前情回顧
Previously on "Marvel's Agents Of S.H.I.E.L.D."...
我需要燒灼他的傷口
I need to cauterize his wound.
是傳送
It's a transmission.
信號源是地球地表
It's coming from the surface of the Earth.
那么那里確實有人
So there's someone out there.
我們得找到他們
We need to find them.
你還真是在這塊破石頭上為自己雕刻出了
Well, you have carved out a little life for yourself
一份生活  是吧
on this grim little rock, haven't you?
不  艾比  你賣掉了她
No, Abby, you can't! You sold her.
安靜
Silence.
我就是干這個的
This is what I do.
我的朋友有生命危險
My friend's life is on the line,
我會想到辦法的
so I'll figure something out.
你是對的
You were right.
我就說她會找下來的
I told you she'd find her way down here.
漫威出品
我拯救了人類
I rescued humanity.
你知道嗎
Did you know that?
你可能不知道的是
What you may not know
我做出了多少犧牲
is how much I've sacrificed to do it.
在我來這兒之前  這里是一片廢墟
Before I arrived, this place was nothing but wreckage,
一個死亡生物體的腐爛外殼
the rotted shell of a dead organism.
但我看到了它的潛力
But I saw it for what it could be.
我有遠見
I had vision.
現在  多虧你
And now, thanks to you,
這遠見終于要成為現實了
that vision has finally come to fruition.
你抽了我的血
You've taken my blood.
你還想從我這兒得到什么
What more do you need from me?
盡管我為這些人類做了這么多
Despite all I did for these humans,
我發現他們還是堅信他們的神
I found them clinging to their gods,
他們的童話故事
their fairy tales,
其中一個就是  震波女
one of which was...Quake.
那些老者  愿他們安息
The old ones, rest their souls --
他們會講一個故事
they used to tell the story
說神盾局有一天會從過去
of how S.H.I.E.L.D. would return one day
回來救他們
from the past to save them.
現在你來了
Now here you are.
不是自愿的
Not my choice.
但你還和另一個人類同時出現了
Yet you show up at the exact same time as another human,
她手腕上沒有印記
with no marks on her wrist
能力也遠超她的身份
and a skill set beyond her station.
珍瑪
Jemma.
我知道你想表達點什么
I know you're trying to say something,
但我聽不太明白
but I'm just not sure what.
也許你們不只是童話故事
Perhaps you are more than a fairy tale.
你們來了多少人
How many of you are here?
沒別人了
No one else.
我想相信你  黛西
I want to believe you, Daisy.
我能叫你"黛西"嗎
May I call you "Daisy"?
這比"世界毀滅者"隨和多了
It's a lot less formal than "Destroyer of Worlds".
我對那篇童話故事有自己的理解
You see, I have my own interpretation of the fairy tale.
我覺得你們是來幫我的
I think you're here to help me.
那不太可能
That seems unlikely.
是嗎
Does it?
你的出現可是招來了不少興趣
Word of your presence has piqued much interest.
競價者已經在路上了
In fact, bidders are on their way.
等我拿到賣了你的錢
And with the price I'll fetch for you,
我就終于可以
I'll finally have the means
永遠離開這個可怕的地方了
to leave this horrendous place once and for all.
你憑什么覺得我會乖乖聽話
What makes you think I'd go along with that?
因為
Because, of course,
你朋友長得這么美
your friend's face is so beautiful.
你不想讓她繼續美下去嗎
Don't you want to make sure it stays that way?
神盾局特工
第五季 第四集
你在這里干什么
What are you doing here?
他們叫停了所有拖曳船作業
They shut down all the Trawler flights.
不知道為什么
No idea why...
那他們現在還讓駕駛員來當粉碎工了
So now they even have the pilots working as crushers, I guess.
那是我在這兒學來的說法
That's a little slang I picked up here.
"粉碎工"  就是
"Crusher." It's when you --
菲爾  我聽得懂"粉碎工"
Phil. I get "Crusher."
-黛西有消息嗎  -沒有
- Anything on Daisy? ‭- Nothing.
我們才有機會弄清地表的情況
Just when we have a chance of getting answers on the surface,
卻失蹤了兩個人
two of our people go missing.
有發現嗎
Anything?
我去問了在停泊區工作的人
Been checking with the guys working the docking bays
想問問黛西是否搭船去了別的層
to see if maybe Daisy hopped a ship to move between levels,
但我說不好
but I don't know.
我猜她沒有
I assume she didn't.
該緊張了嗎
Is it time to panic yet?
可能吧
Possibly.
我找遍了這層
I've covered every square inch of this floor.
完全不見黛西
No sign of Daisy.
我不喜歡這樣
I don't like this.
她可能被抓了  她可能
She could be captured. She could --
你們不是來站在這里聊天的
You're not here ‭to stand around and gossip.
我們都在說話  為什么電我
We were all talking. Why me?
因為你塊頭更大
'Cause you're bigger.
這樣更有趣
Makes it funnier.
繼續工作
Keep working!
樓下的大佬在招待客人
Big man downstairs is entertaining.
舉行星際拍賣  所以我們得提供
An intergalactic auction means that we have to provide
更多的鐵讓卡塞亞斯去賣
more iron for Kasius to sell off.
所以我們要三班倒
So we are working triple shifts.
我聽命于藍臉大佬  跟你們一樣
I answer to the fat cat Blues, same as you.
只是我必須去向他們解釋
Only I have to go and explain to them
為什么我們沒完成定額
why we are not meeting our quotas.
所以務必在今天結束之前完成定額
So make sure we do by the end of today.
除了你
Except you.
你跟我來
You're with me.
他叫加納
Guy's name is Gunner.
自以為很厲害
Thinks he's a tough guy.
欠了我很多代幣
Owes me a lot of tokens.
我需要你去揍他一頓
I need you to rough him up.
你需要我干嗎
W-- You need me to do what?
揍扁他
Beat his ass.
可靠消息說
Look, I got it on good authority
加納在等來自35層的一個包裹
that Gunner is waiting on a package from Level 35 --
那是高度機密  只有克里佬才能去的科研層
now, that is a high-security, Kreepers-only technology floor.
他欠我錢  又從藍臉人那里拿設備
He's in debt to me ‭and getting tech from the Blues?
我不喜歡這樣
I don't like that.
但你已經有打手了
But you already got enforcers.
為什么還要我來做
Why do you need me to do it?
我以前有澤夫
Well, I had Zev.
他是條蛇
He was a snake.
現在他是蟑螂食了
Now he's roach food.
你照過鏡子嗎
And have you looked in a mirror?
你是頭野獸
You're a beast.
去做個野獸吧
Go be one.
借過
Excuse me.
他們培育的
They grow it.
什么
What?
你在想肉是從哪里來的
You're wondering ‭where the meat comes from.
有個什么實驗室  他們在那里培育的
There's some kind of lab where they grow it or something.
只是恰好猜中了
Was that just a lucky guess,
還是你剛剛讀取了我的想法
or did you just... read my thoughts?
我聽到了
I heard them, really.
泰瑞根變異后我就有了這能力
That's what I got after Terrigenesis.
你是異人
You're Inhuman.
所以你才能預見招式
That's how you anticipated the moves,
順便說句  這可不好
which is not cool, by the way --
未經允許就讀人心思
reading people's minds without permission.
我聽到什么就是什么
I hear what I hear.
相信我  他們關掉的時候輕松得多
Believe me -- it's kind of a relief when they turn it off.
好了
And there we go.
好了  所有人出去
All right, everyone out.
你留下
Not you.
你很特別
No, ‭you're something special.
他們要看你單獨表現
You get a private viewing.
你沒得選  邁克
Yeah, I don't think you have a choice, Mack,
要是我們想不被吉爾找麻煩的話
if we want to keep Grill off our backs.
那我們得去揍一頓這個加納
So we gotta go rough up this guy Gunner.
跟這鬼地方其他的一切一樣合理
Yeah. Makes as much sense as anything else in this place.
也許你和悠悠球可以跟他談談
Maybe you and Yo-Yo can just talk to him.
避免爆發沖突
Avoid the all-out assault.
我們兩個
Both of us?
我已經失去兩名特工了
I'm already missing two agents.
我要按邁克的邏輯來  組團行動
I'm going with Mack's philosophy that we stick together here.
可算聽我的了
Finally.
只要你們在吉爾之前回來  就應該沒事
As long as you're back before Grill, we should be fine.
而且這也是個機會
And it gets us an opportunity.
-對  你和我的機會  -沒錯
- Yeah. That's you and me. ‭- Yup.
吉爾剛剛告訴了我們35層的情報
Grill just tipped us off to Level 35 --
克里人科技  我們得去看看
Kree technology? We have to check that out.
我們沒有武器  沒有情報
We have no weapons, no intel.
希望35層能給我們點優勢
Well, I'm hoping Level 35 gets us an edge,
至少能讓我們在地表存活
or at least something that'll help us survive on the surface
找到維吉爾的無線電伙伴
till we can find Virgil's radio pal.
你有辦法去機密層嗎
You got access to a secure floor?
沒有  但我認識個人
No, but... I think I know a guy.
你讓異人們互相搏斗
So you're making them fight? Inhumans?
這地方就是干這個的
That's what this place is for --
為消遣他們而打斗
fighting for entertainment?
不止是為了消遣
Not just for entertainment.
為了利益
For profit.
卡塞亞斯的利益
Kasius' profit.
他要什么
What does he want?
要你展示一下技藝
A demonstration of your skills.
要是我現在剛好不想表演呢
Maybe I don't feel ‭like performing on cue today.
除非你有花生
Unless you've got peanuts.
你應該快點進入狀態
Maybe you should get in the mood. Fast.
為了你的朋友
For your friend.
好吧
Okay. Fine.
我不是這個意思
That wasn't what I meant.
我不知道
I had no idea
你這里竟然有世界毀滅者
that you had the Destroyer of Worlds in your stable.
我忘了說嗎
Did I forget to mention it?
消息傳開了
Word's gotten around,
許多商人正在來的路上
and a host of traders are on their way presently.
也許我現在就可以先開個價買下她
Well, perhaps I can make a preemptive bid for her now.
芭莎  那就太好了
Oh, Basha. That would be lovely.
我可以出比任何人都高的價...
I can make a far greater offer than any --
很可惜  價格商議
Unfortunately, discussion of price
是在晚飯期間進行的
will take place over dinner.
既然你如此喜歡在你的艦船上用餐
And since you so prefer dining on your own ship,
恐怕你沒有參與競價的機會了  不是嗎
I fear that takes ‭you out of the running...no?
好吧
Ah, well.
祝你安全回到你的...
Safe journey home to your --
你用的那個有趣的詞是什么來著
what was the colorful phrase you used? --
"破石頭"
"Grim little rock."
她人好像不錯
She seems nice.
你是來拿報酬的吧
I suppose you're here for payment.
我可給你帶來了震波女
Well, I did bring you Quake.
是的
So you did.
給
Here.
這是銠嗎
Is that Rhodium?
你對高價金屬很有眼光
You have an eye for high-value metals.
這比你在樓上的全部的身家都值錢
This'll be worth more than all your credits upstairs.
是的
Yes, it will.
我想謝謝你把她帶來給我
I want to thank you for bringing her to me.
但是錫納拉擔心那個預言
But Sinara is concerned about the prophecy --
還會有其他人從過去穿越過來
that others from the past might have come, as well.
看來你也擔心
Guess that means you are, too.
預言很難破解
Prophecies are hard to decipher.
有可能是兩個人  也有可能是20個
Could be 2 people, could be 20.
如果你沒殺掉所有知情的人
Well, maybe the prophecy wouldn't be such a mystery
也許預言就不會如此神秘了
if you didn't kill everyone that knew anything about it.
是的
Yes.
人生充滿了遺憾
Life is full of regrets.
不過...
Still.
我要怎么幫你
How can I help?
如果你碰到任何其他的時間旅行者
Should you come across any additional time travelers
或是任何幫助他們的人  我會很感激
or anyone who helped them, I'd be grateful...
也很慷慨
and generous.
我看看能幫你查到什么吧
Let me see what I can find for you.
你難道不清楚全部情況嗎
So, you're telling me you don't see the whole picture?
我想告訴你  但是我覺得你已經知道了
I'd fill you in, but I feel like you already know.
我讀過泰伊的思想  我當然知道
I've read Tye's mind. Of course I know.
那個儀式
The Ceremonies --
他們讓異人互相打斗
They are making Inhumans fight each other.
然后等人競價嗎
And people bid on them?
你對這沒意見嗎
Are you okay with this?
我已經接受了
I've come to terms with it.
其他人呢
And everyone else?
其他人不知道
The others don't know.
他們絕對不能知道
They can never know.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
-他們有權利反擊  -但是我們必須
- They have the right to fight back. ‭- But we have to.
-你不能袖手旁觀  -不能告訴他們
- You can't just sit here and do nothing. - You can't tell them.
-誰也不能說  -你這樣沒道理
- You can't tell anyone. - You've gotta make better sense than this,
-如果其他人發現了  -因為
- If the others find out, - 'cause I mean --
他們阻止不了這件事的發生
they can't do what has to be done.
我們這么做  展示我們的異能
We do this, demonstrate our powers,
跟買下我們的人走
and go with whomever buys us
因為我們一走  我們的家人就能得到補償
because our families get compensated once we're gone.
你是說他們得到賣掉你們的錢嗎
You mean they get paid to sell you.
我是說他們有更好的生存機會
I mean they have ‭a better shot at survival.
生存就是一切
Survival is everything.
這簡直是瘋了
This is insane.
這就是生活
This is life.
否則  我們的家人就要付出代價
Otherwise, our families could pay the price.
你也有你關心的人  這我聽到了
You have people you care about -- I heard that much.
如果你在乎他們  我建議你遵守規則
If you care about them, I suggest you play the game.
如果他們讓我們倆打
And if they pit us against each other,
我建議你努力去贏
I suggest you try to win.
因為我會的
'Cause I will.
-干嘛  -抱歉
- Come on. - Sorry.
我們需要談談
We need to talk.
說句  "迪克  你好嗎
"Say, Deke. How you doing?
你看起來很好  能和你談談嗎"
You look really good. Can we have a word?"
這么說很難嗎
See? It's not that hard.
不過我本來也要找你們
I was coming to find you guys, anyway,
因為我有些時候沒見到你們了
'cause I haven't seen you in a little while.
我還希望黛西跟你在一起呢
I was hoping Daisy was with you.
據我們所知  她在找你
Last we heard, she was looking for you.
是  她找到我了
Yeah. She found me.
我幾個小時前還跟她在一起
I was just with her a couple hours ago.
一切順利
And it's -- it's -- it's all good.
我幫她進入了低層的醫療層
I-I helped her onto a lower medical floor.
我們覺得你們另一個朋友就在那里
It's where we think your other friend is.
她沒回來  也沒來報信
She never came back or checked in.
她說了什么要停止聯系
She said something ‭about no further contact --
間諜的那種事
spy stuff.
她怎么說的來著  "靜默模式"
How'd she put it? "Silent mode"?
-消失  -對  就是這個
- Going dark. - Yeah. That.
我告訴她你們會找她的
And I told her that you'd wonder,
她說  "別擋道
and she said, "Get out of my way.
我就是干這個的  我的朋友有生命危險
This is what I do. My friend's life is on the line.
我會想到辦法的"
I'll figure something out."
沒錯  聽著像是黛西說的
Yeah. That sounds like Daisy.
抱歉她沒跟我在一起  我也希望她在
Sorry I don't have her. I wish I did.
沒事  我們是來找你的
It's all right. We came for you.
你對35層知道多少
What do you know about Level 35?
每隔幾層就會有一層克里人機密層
Every few floors, there's a secure Kree level.
4層是拘留層
Level 4 is holding --
我就是在那層認識你們的
that's where I met you fine folks.
然后17層是工程層
And then Level 17 is engineering.
但我從沒去過35層  怎么了
But I've never seen 35. Why?
我們想找些克里技術
We're hoping to find some Kree technology.
任何能幫到我們的都行
Anything that'll help us.
我們需要探查地表
We need to investigate the surface.
地表  為什么不呢
The surface. Yeah, why not?
對啊  去太陽中心太慢了
No, yeah, it'll take too long to get to the center of the sun.
我知道這計劃不太尋常
I know it's an unconventional plan.
你們到底有什么毛病
What is actually wrong with you people
總是去你們不該去的地方
that you keep going places you are not supposed to be going?
你們都這么有自殺傾向嗎
Are you all very suicidal?
我們有我們的理由
We have reasons.
絕不是好理由
Not good ones.
現在是了
We do now.
維吉爾待在拖曳船上的時候
Virgil's time in the Trawler?
他在和地表通訊
He was communicating with the surface.
維吉爾  回復  收到嗎
Virgil. Come in. Do you read?
我們已經三天沒有你的消息了
We haven't heard from you in three days.
請回復  維吉爾
Please respond. Virgil.
你找到代表團了嗎
Have you secured the delegation?
他們都死了  卡塞亞斯以為他們都死了
Those people are all dead. Kasius thinks they're all dead.
我知道
I know.
我需要去拿幾樣東西
I-I need to go get a few things.
現在你有興趣了
So now you're interested?
地表上的那些人  如果我們能找到他們
Those people up there... if we can find them,
那對所有人都是最有利的
that's in everyone's best interest.
那是加納嗎
Is that Gunner?
是他
That's Gunner.
走路自然點
Try to walk casual.
你能看見我的話  我走得很自然了
If you can see me, ‭that's me walking casual.
好吧
That's fair.
不過盡量別沖動行事
But try not to do anything rash.
你想聊聊嗎
Do you want to talk about it
還是要整天這么明顯地暗示我
or make not very subtle comments all day?
有話直說  小烏龜
Spit it out, turtleman.
我們還要去揍人了嗎
So, we're beating people up now?
我們做的事已經很過分了
It's bad enough ‭what we've already done.
你是在說吉爾的副手嗎
Are you talking ‭about Grill's right-hand man?
我那是為了救人  救你
I did it to save lives, your life.
是啊  可現在他死了
Yeah. Now the guy's dead.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry about that,
但無論多少次我都會選擇你犧牲他
but I choose you over him every time.
好吧
Yeah.
我只是不希望我們在這里迷失自我
I just don't want us losing ourselves here.
看看菲茲在框架里的樣子
Look what happened ‭to Fitz in the Framework.
這不一樣
This is different.
我知道不一樣  這地方是真實的
Yeah, I know it's different. This place is real.
沒錯  危險和暴力都是真實的
Yeah, exactly. ‭Real danger, real violence.
我們為了生存要保護自己
We protect ourselves to survive.
是  但為了生存一定要傷害別人嗎
Yeah. Do we have to hurt people to do it?
如果現實一點  可能真的要
If we're being practical, maybe.
好吧
Yeah, well...
我從小就被教己不所欲勿施于人
I was raised do unto others as you would have them do to you.
你是在郊區長大的
Yeah, you were raised in the suburbs.
我不是在內珀維爾長大的
I didn't grow up in Naperville.
我在波托西長大  那座城市和這里一樣
I grew up in Potosí, a city just like this.
靠恐懼運轉
It operates on fear.
而你恨那個地方
Yeah. And you hated it there.
但我從那里學到了東西
Yeah, but I learned from it.
我們不一定要傷害他來恐嚇他
We don't have to hurt him to scare him.
看看那個混蛋
Look at that bastard.
他欠人錢  還想再借
He owes money, and he's still trying to get more.
或許真該嚇唬他一下
Maybe he does need a shake-up.
別擔心  我們不會迷失自我的
And don't worry -- we won't lose ourselves.
我保證
I promise.
珍瑪
Jemma.
我渴了
I'm thirsty.
真相不是一個相對概念  對不對
The truth is not ‭a relative concept, is it?
是主觀看法嗎
A subjective conceit?
那就想象一下
Then imagine my disappointment
我發現你和珍瑪隱藏了真相后的失望
to discover you and Jemma did, in fact, hide the truth.
錫納拉說珍瑪救人的時候有個朋友幫了她
Sinara said Jemma had a friend who assisted in saving a life,
看起來是認識她  而且懂這些東西
seemed to know her, seemed to understand.
我本想問西蒙斯的
I would ask Simmons,
但她由于某些原因沒法聽到我說話
but she can't hear me for some twisted reason.
我已經告訴你了
I already told you.
行了
Please.
我無法容忍謊言
I can't abide untruths.
你也沒必要
And it's unnecessary
想知道真相  是可以很快的
when we can get to the facts ever so quickly.
當然了  我無法知道
Of course, there's no way
你是不是說了實話
I can tell for certain if you're being honest.
但他可以
But he can.
我已經告訴你了  只有我和西蒙斯
I already told you. It's just me and Simmons.
珍瑪
‭Jemma,
你幫助里斯時  幫你的那個女人是誰
who was the woman helping you when you helped Reese?
我不知道
I have no idea.
那天大集市人很多
There were lots of people in the Exchange that day.
我可不認識每個人
I don't know who they all were.
她們說的是實話
They're telling the truth.
她們兩個都是
Both of them.
你們是一起穿越過來的  還是分開過來的
Did you come through time together or separately?
我不明白這有什么關系
I don't understand why that matters.
因為預言提到了神盾局
Because the prophecy spoke of S.H.I.E.L.D.
如果是這樣  你可能根本不知道
And if they did, ‭you may not even be aware of it.
我們是一起過來的
We came through together.
沒有別人  就我們兩個
No one else. Just us.
很好
Very well.
跟我們說說那個神奇的故事吧
Tell us that miraculous story.
不要漏掉任何細節
Spare no detail.
只有我們兩個
We were alone.
我們失去了一個人  杰弗里·梅斯
We lost one. Jeffrey Mace.
是菲茲殺了他  菲茲是我們的一個隊員
Fitz killed him. One of our team members.
菲茲是珍瑪的...他們是愛人
Fitz was Jemma's -- they were in love.
他受不了了
And he couldn't handle it.
說實話  我們都受不了了
Honestly, none of us really could.
他要離開神盾局
He was gonna leave S.H.I.E.L.D.,
所以我把珍瑪帶出來單獨談話
so I took Jemma out to talk alone.
我們去了一個餐館
We went to a diner.
我們正談著話  突然有人沖了進來
We were just talking when these guys came in,
他們把我們抓走了
and they grabbed us.
他們把我們打暈了  然后"噗"的一下
They knocked us out, and, boom --
我們就到這里了
we ended up here.
珍瑪  現在你要跟我講同樣的故事
Jemma, now you tell me the same story --
你們是怎么到這里來的
how you two ended up here.
還有  珍瑪
And, Jemma?
你講的故事最好跟她講的一模一樣
It had best be a story in perfect accord with hers.
在"框架"里的最后一次任務
I was so distraught after our last mission --
讓我心思很亂
in the Framework --
菲茲殺掉了梅斯  他變壞了
when Fitz killed Mace -- and Fitz was worse.
他決定離開神盾局
He decided to leave S.H.I.E.L.D.
我們的團隊似乎要分道揚鑣了
It seemed our team was breaking up.
黛西把我帶到一個餐館單獨聊聊
Daisy took me to a diner to talk alone.
我想是為了讓我好受一些
To make me feel better, I guess.
然后有人沖了進來
And then these men came.
他們抓住了我們  把我們打暈...
They grabbed us, they knocked us out...
然后我們就到這里了
and we ended up here.
那好
Good, then.
我跟你有同樣的擔憂
I share your concern,
但我們還得做準備
but we have preparations to make.
而且  記住
And, remember,
在忙這個的不只你一個人
you're not the only one working on this.
我猜這不是
I imagine it's not as simple
直接乘電梯到35層那么簡單
as taking ‭the elevator down to 35.
對  我們到不了那一層
No. We can't access it.
但我可以停到下面一層  然后找路上去
But I can get us in below it, find my way in.
我會在35層叫電梯
I'll call the elevator from Level 35 itself.
你們抓緊了
You guys hang tight.
你相信他嗎
You trust him?
你知道我不的
You know me better than that.
歡迎來到35層
Welcome to Level 35.
不必鼓掌了
Yeah, well, hold the applause.
剛剛怎么回事
What the hell just happened?
我替你掩蓋了
I covered for you.
怎么做到的
Yeah, but how?
我的異人能力  不僅僅是讀心
My Inhuman power -- it isn't just reading minds.
你也可以讓別人讀到你的想法
You can let other people read your mind, too.
你把我說的話告訴了西蒙斯
So you told Simmons what I said.
對
Yeah.
他們不知道我還會這個
They don't know I can do that.
不是說要遵守規則嗎
What about playing the game?
黛西  聽著
Daisy, listen,
剛剛那里不僅只有你在
it wasn't just your minds in there.
那是我最接近卡塞亞斯的一次
That was as close ‭as I've ever been to Kasius.
我第一次讀他的機會
‭My first chance to read his.
好吧
Right.
你讀到了什么
So, what did you see?
羞恥
Shame.
他討厭這里
He hates this place.
等他的慶典都結束了
When his gala is all done,
卡塞亞斯不僅要離開
Kasius isn't just leaving --
他還要抹去一切
he wants it all erased.
他要摧毀站點嗎
He's gonna destroy the station?
還有這里的所有人
Along with everyone on it.
我的家人
My family.
每一個家庭
Every family.
但我也可能看到他認為你多厲害
But I could also see how powerful he thinks you are...
以及你清楚自己有多強大
and how powerful you know you are.
很好
Good.
或許我們該改改他的游戲規則了
Maybe it's time we change the rules on his game.
什么  你們干什么
Who -- What are you --
吉爾派我們來的
Grill sent us.
他想要錢
He wants his money.
是嗎  去他的
Yeah? Screw Grill.
我跟他說了  會給他錢的  就一定會給
I told him he'd get his money, and he will.
他覺得你能嚇住我
He thinks you're gonna scare me?
我最好嚇住
I should.
否則這個大塊頭也會嚇倒你的
Because if I don't, big man here will.
這是什么地方
What is this place?
實驗室  可能是研究開發部
Lab. Maybe R&D.
研究開發  也行啊
R&D. That works.
叫吉爾別緊張
Tell Grill to relax.
我在湊了
I'm putting it together.
-誰都不想要麻煩  -很好
- No one wants any trouble. - ‭Good.
那就別惹麻煩
Then don't cause any,
因為我可不知道我朋友會做什么
'cause I don't know what my friend will do.
你朋友最好冷靜點
Your friend just needs to calm down.
別緊張
Take it easy. Take it easy.
你在等的包裹
Now, this package you're waiting for...
我們可以讓它消失的
you know we can make it disappear.
你說什么
What did you just say?
如果這地方是做科研的
If this place is all science,
那肯定有什么我們用得上的東西
then there's got ‭to be something here we can use.
我們只需要找到它
We just need to find it.
蟑螂嗎
Roaches?
不
No.
我是說  如果你耍花樣
I'm saying if you try anything,
我們完全可以去找到你的這個包裹
it wouldn't be hard for us to go after this package of yours
讓你永遠拿不到它
and make it ‭so it never gets to you.
你不能那么做
You can't do that.
經常有東西消失不見嘛
‭Things go missing all the time.
我發誓  我會殺了你的
I swear, I'll kill you.
等等  那是什么
Wait. What is that?
是給加納的包裹吧
It's the package meant for Gunner, isn't it?
大概是吧
Probably.
最近有很多空位
There's been ‭a lot of vacancies lately.
肯定是需要添補上了
Must be time to start filling them.
什么人會做這么下作的威脅
What kind of man makes a threat so low?
你真有病
You're sick.
還錢給吉爾  就沒人會拿你的東西了
Just pay Grill, and no one will take your stuff.
邁克
Mack.
否則  我們就拿走你的包裹
But if you don't, we'll take that package,
丟進粉碎機里
and we'll throw it in the crushing mill.
邁克  看
Mack, look.
誰會威脅一個孩子
Who threatens a child?
誰會威脅奪走一個嬰兒
Who would threaten to tear a baby away from someone
這機會如此難得
‭when the chance is so rare?
對不起  我不知道
Sorry. I didn't know.
我沒看到
I didn't see.
這里的孩子害怕
Kids are scarce here
就是因為你這種人
because of people like you
你們只知道暴力和死亡
who only understand violence and death!
我希望你永遠得不到這個殊榮
I hope you never get the privilege.
你反正也肯定做不好
You'd mess it up, anyway.
你這樣的人不配得到孩子
People like you don't deserve a child.
邁克
Mack!
邁克  別
Mack, no!
邁克
Mack!
邁克  別  邁克
Mack, no! Mack!
邁克
Mack!
瞧
See?
他們用新生兒當商品
They're using newborns as a commodity?
你以為這里的規矩是怎樣的
How do you think ‭things are done around here?
這是人們可以生孩子的唯一方式
It's the only way anyone can have kids.
什么  "唯一方式"
I'm sorry -- "The only way"?
已經沒人會懷孕了
People don't get pregnant anymore.
這可好
Super.
真是完全反烏托邦了
And the vibe goes full-dystopian.
他們做了什么  給所有人絕育嗎
What did they do -- sterilize the whole population?
我們認為是通過食物
We think they do it through the food
這樣他們可以決定誰可以有孩子
so they can decide who has children.
多久了
How long?
他們一直想進行控制
They've always tried to control it.
我是最后一批以老法子降生的孩子之一
I was one of the last ones that was born the old-fashioned way,
后來卡塞亞斯決定更簡單的辦法是
until Kasius decided that it was easiest to just --
自己創造孩子  但為什么
Create the children themselves. But why?
他們是想多樣化人類嗎
Are they trying to diversify the human population?
卡塞亞斯才不在乎人類
Kasius doesn't care about humans.
他只想增加他們轉化的基因概率
He just wants to increase the genetic chances they turn.
變成異人
To Inhumans.
他們要更值錢
They're much more valuable that way.
值錢  對誰更值錢
Valuable? Valuable to whom?
迪克  下面在拍賣什么
Deke, what is he auctioning off down there?
你以為他在賣石頭嗎
You think he's selling rocks?
整個過程都很讓人不爽
The whole process is pretty upsetting,
所以我們盡力不去考慮細節
so we try not to think about the details.
菲爾
Phil.
我有發現
I found something.
什么
What is it?
他
Him.
好吧  疼啊
Okay.
梅
May?
實驗室獲得了新的可用樣本
The lab got a new sample they're supposed to use...
異人基因樣本
...for Inhuman genes.
黛西
Daisy.
他們從昨天就抓到了她
And they've been holding her since yesterday...
那上面是那么說的嗎  因為你...
Is that what that thing says? Because if you --
但你卻說你早上還在幫她
...even though you said you were helping her this morning.
要不是你出賣了她  為什么要撒謊
Why would you lie about Daisy unless you sold her out?
好吧  我現在大概該解釋一下了
Okay, well, this is probably the part where I should explain.
不
No.
現在  梅要打爆你的臉
This is the part ‭where May breaks your face.
你解不解釋  是其次的
You explaining -- kind of secondary.
好吧  你們生氣了  我懂
Okay. You're mad. I get that.
他們在用她繁殖嗎
Are they using her for breeding?
看上去是那樣  但那不是卡塞亞斯想要她的原因
It seems that way, but that's not why Kasius wanted her.
那么你是出賣了她
So you did sell her out.
是的  但是...
Yes, but it's mo--
各位  我們其實...
Hey, fellas, ‭we actually --
我們就是迷路了
we were -- just got a little bit turned around.
這是35層嗎  我們其實在找...
Uh, is this Level 35? We were actually looking --
好吧  那我們要打了
Oh, okay, we're fighting.
又有克里佬來了
More Kreepers.
菲爾  你帶迪克上樓去
Phil, you take Deke upstairs.
讓他交待  我來抵住他們
Make him talk. I'll hold them off.
我不會丟下你一人的
I'm not leaving you here alone.
-快走  -梅  你的腿
- Go. - May. Your leg.
你還沒完全恢復
You're still not 100%.
我可以的  走
I got this. Go.
好了
Okay.
不流血了  感覺如何
The bleeding's stopped. How's it feel?
挺好的
It's fine.
那就好  不會太緊嗎
Good. Not too tight?
不  挺緊的  但不會太緊
No. Snug. Not too tight.
那就好
Okay.
那樣的話
In that case...
你們真的得停止那么做了
I really need you people to stop doing that.
黛西在哪
Where's Daisy?
-我沒辦法  -沒辦法嗎
- Look, I had to do that. - Oh, you had to?
是的
Yeah, I had to.
有人死了
People had died,
卡塞亞斯本會毫不猶豫地殺更多人
and Kasius wouldn't have hesitated to kill hundreds more,
而黛西似乎毫不介意
and Daisy didn't even seem to care at all.
所以  相信我  她不在會更安全
So, trust me -- it's safer with her out of the mix.
我不信任你
I don't trust you.
我是做了沒辦法的事
Well, I did what needed to be done.
得了  你不是第一次去領賞了
Oh, please. That wasn't the first time you went for a payday.
你才不想救人
You weren't out to save lives.
你是在掙錢
You made a profit.
這兩者不非得是相抵觸的
The two ‭aren't mutually exclusive.
-別假裝你的動機是純粹的  -得了
- So don't pretend your motives were pure. - Oh, please.
你有好多事還不知道呢
There's so much ‭you don't even know that --
你又在這么做了  是吧
And now you're doing it again, aren't you?
你才不想幫助地表上的人
You don't want to help those people on the surface.
你想把他們出賣給卡塞亞斯
You want to turn them over to Kasius for --
你根本不了解我
You don't know me, man!
我才九歲
I was 9 -- okay? --
我母親就被拖走  殺害了
when my mother got ‭dragged away and murdered.
卡塞亞斯殺了所有的老者
Kasius got rid of all the elders,
所有聰明人  她就是其中之一
all the smart people, and she was one of them.
她死后  我父親繼承了事業
And after she was gone, my dad took up the cause.
他繼續為她奮斗
He carried the torch for her.
我長大些后  我求他不要那么做
And as I got older, I begged him not to.
我說  他們也會抓走他  我說對了
I said that they were gonna get him, too, and I was right.
他被送去喂了蟑螂  就像其他人那樣
He got sent to the roaches, just like the rest of them.
所以聽到他的聲音感覺很奇怪
That's why it was pretty strange to hear his voice.
那是你父親
That was your father?
如果他在上面  還活著
If he's alive up there,
我不僅希望你成功
I don't just want you to succeed --
我還需要在場
I need to be there when you do.
這故事很好
Oh. That's a good story.
但你凈編故事
But stories are what you do,
別介意我暫且還不信
so excuse me ‭if I don't buy it just yet.
你想幫忙  就證明給我們看
You wanna help us, ‭you're gonna need to prove it.
怎么證明
How?
首先是你憑黛西拿到的酬勞
Let's start with the payment you got for Daisy.
有別人比你更需要那個
Someone else needs that more than you do.
真是比被捅傷還要肉疼
That's more painful than getting stabbed.
這能為我買到信任嗎
That buy me some trust?
能為你買到時間
It buys you some time.
但現在
But for now,
我覺得沒有你  我們會更安全
I think we're safer with you out of the mix.
等等
Hey, wait, wait, wait!
Wait!
-梅有消息嗎  -拜托
- Any word from May? - Come on!
沒有
No.
這么閑站著可要小心了
Wanna be careful standing around.
吉爾很快就會回來
Grill's gonna be back soon.
你想談談了嗎
Are you ready to talk yet?
沒什么好說的
There's nothing to say.
我還叫你別迷失了自己
I mean, there I was, telling you not to lose yourself...
誰不喜歡諷刺呢
Who doesn't love irony, right?
邁克  加納說中了你的軟肋
Mack, Gunner hit your weak spots.
你當然會生氣了
Of course you reacted.
我真是聽不下去
I just couldn't listen to him.
他不知道你失去了什么
He doesn't know what you've lost
還有你是多棒的老爸
or how great of a dad you are.
但如果我不是呢
But what if I'm not?
不是什么
Not what?
一個好爸爸
A great dad.
邁克  別這樣  夠了
Mack, please. Stop it.
不
No.
霍普死時  真正的霍普
When Hope died -- the real Hope --
她都沒回到家
she never came home,
雖然過了幾周
and, still, it took me weeks
我才能走進她的育嬰室
before I could walk into her nursery
把東西都清走  但我最終做到了
and take everything away, but I did it...eventually.
那肯定很艱難
It must have been hard.
但這個霍普
But this Hope...
我的霍普
my Hope...
框架里的那個
in the Framework...
她
She, uh...
要更難
This is harder.
我好想她
I miss her so much.
要心痛多了
It's so much worse.
想想看
Imagine that.
失去真正的孩子后  我撐了下來
I survived the pain of losing my real child,
但卻無法忘記失去一個假孩子的痛
but I can't get over the pain of losing a fake one,
那么我是什么樣的父親
so what kind of a father does that make me?
或許加納說對了我
Maybe Gunner was right about me.
或許我真的已經迷失了
Maybe I really am already lost. I --
霍普或許不是真的
Hope might not have been real,
但你對她的愛是真的
but your love for her was.
所以  你是個好爸爸  好人
And that makes you ‭a great father and a good man.
我們會不忘初心地在這里撐下去
We'll get through this place intact.
一起撐下去
Together.
好嗎
Okay?
野獸邁克
Hey, Monster Mack!
加納剛還了我的債
Gunner just paid me off.
看來你比我想的還厲害啊
Seems like you're twice the beast I thought you were.
很高興有你在  邁克
Glad to have you, Mack.
你很合適這里
You fit right in.
你處理好我們的新客人了嗎
And you've dealt with our newest guest?
慷慨的主人卡塞亞斯
Your gracious host Kasius
想向大家表示歡迎
would like to say a few words of welcome.
我真的非常榮幸
It is truly my pleasure
邀請大家來這個奇妙的地方
to invite you to this wondrous place,
這里是一個種族最后的堡壘
the last bastion of a species,
也是我長久以來以為傲的家
a place I've been proud to call home for so long.
你們是第一批
You are the first to arrive
前來觀看無約束力量的展示
for an exhibition of unbridled powers
并刺激感官的
to excite the senses...
之后就是我們的壓軸好戲
...all leading up to our main event.
一個威力強大的異人  被以為早已不在
One powerful Inhuman, long thought gone,
現在  她將豐富一位幸運資助人的生活
now here to enrich one lucky patron's life.
震波女  世界毀滅者
Quake, Destroyer of Worlds.
有人  或許正是此刻這房間里的人
Someone, maybe someone in this room right now,
將贏得大獎
will win this prize.
她的力量  就會成為你的
Her power...will be your power.
那么
So...
我們開始前  誰有什么要求嗎
...are there any requests as we begin?
別管什么展示了
Forget your exhibition.
她是世界毀滅者
She's the Destroyer of Worlds.
直接讓她決戰生死吧
She should fight to the death.